Guide to the Records WAG.212
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
New York Hard Hat News Records
Bulk, 1986-2002
1941-2002
WAG.212
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
10.0 linear feet in 10 boxes
The New York Hard Hat News is a quarterly newspaper for construction workers in the New York metropolitan area that covers topics of concern to workers in the building trades, with a strong emphasis on efforts to both increase union democracy as well as combat corruption. The collection contains materials collected in order to prepare and print the paper, including clippings, subject files and administrative files.
New York Hard Hat News.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Jane LaTour and Guy Robinson, August 2002
Arrangement
Materials are arranged in two series: Managing Editor's Files and Editor's Files.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The New York Hard Hat News is a quarterly newspaper for construction workers in the New York metropolitan area. Also known as Hard Hat News, it covers topics of concern to workers in the building trades, with a strong emphasis on efforts to both increase union democracy as well as combat corruption.
Scope and Content Note
Contains materials collected in order to prepare and print New York Hard Hat News, including clippings, subject files and administrative files.
Fitch, Robert, 1938-; LaTour, Jane; New York Hard Hat News.; Building trades |z New York (State) |z New York.; Labor unions |x Corrupt practices |z New York (State); Labor unions |z New York (State)
- Managing Editor's Files
  - Editorial Files, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Bob Fitch Files, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Editorial Files, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Editorial Files, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Editorial Files, Dec 1999 (Box 1)
  - Editorial Files, Winter 2000 (Box 1)
  - Editorial Files, Spring 2001 (Box 1)
  - Editorial Files, Spring 2002 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2002 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 1)
  - Hate Mail, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 1)
  - HHN meetings, minutes and agenda, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - Subscription – returned to Jane LaTour, undated (Box 1)
  - Promotional material, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Journalism Standards, undated (Box 1)
  - Graphics, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Advertisers, 1995-1999 (Box 1)
  - Development Research, 1996-2000 (Box 2)
  - Post office receipts, 1997-2002 (Box 2)
  - Receipts, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Receipts, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Letters of support, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Articles about, 1992-2001 (Box 2)
  - Grant applications, 1999-2001 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Grant "Resist", 1998-2000 (Box 2)
  - Grant application North Star Foundation, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Grant application North Star Foundation, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Trusteeship Local 282, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence and clippings, 1999-2001 (Box 2)
  - Research/clippings, Dec 1998 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence and clippings, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Background and potential stories, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Background, Jul 1998 (Box 3)
  - Background – IBT, Iron workers, Javitz, 1994-1997 (Box 3)
  - Background- construction Industry, clippings, 1960-1997 (Box 3)
  - Clippings – construction industry, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Books about construction, 1995-1998 (Box 3)
  - Historical background- construction industry, clippings, bibliographies, cartoons, 1995-2001 (Box 3)
  - Corruption-clippings, 1941-2001 (Box 3)
  - Corruption – Gambinos, clippings, background material, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence with Jeff Grabelsky, COMET – Cornell Building Trades background, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Articles – COMET, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Temporary Workers, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Clippings – housing, 1980-2000 (Box 3)
  - Clippings – privatization, transportation, 1995-1997 (Box 3)
  - Prevailing wage, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Clippings – health and safety, 1997-2000 (Box 3)
  - Health and safety – clippings and correspondence, 1997-2002 (Box 3)
  - Contractors, 1998-2001 (Box 4)
  - Wages, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Workers Comp/OSHA, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Health and Safety- organizing, 2001-2002 (Box 4)
  - Health and Safety- clippings, 1994-1996, 1998 (Box 4)
  - OSHA publications, 1988 – 1996 (Box 4)
  - Research file – Carpenters, Roy Kay, background files (1998), 1990-1999 (Box 4)
  - Research file – Electricians, 1996-2000 (Box 4)
  - Research file – laborers, clippings, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Research file – Operating engineers, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Research file - Plumbers, 1993-1997 (Box 4)
  - Research file – Sheet metal workers, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Research file – Roofers indictments, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Souvenir Programs, 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - "Dilemma in the Millennium Capital; Needs of the World’s Capitol City" volumes 1&2, office of the Comptroller NYC, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Note books – Jane LaTour, undated (Box 4)
- Editor's Files
  - Editorial Files, undated (Box 5)
  - Editorial Files, undated (Box 5)
  - HHN floppy disks, undated (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 5)
  - Clippings, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
  - Editorial Files, undated (Box 5)
  - Editorial Files, undated (Box 5)
  - Editorial Files, undated (Box 5)
  - Editorial Files, undated (Box 5)
  - Editorial Files, undated (Box 6)
  - Editorial Files, undated (Box 6)
  - Editorial Files, undated (Box 6)
  - Clippings for fall 1990 (Box 6)
  - Editorial Files, undated (Box 6)
  - Editorial Files, Fall 1998 (Box 6)
  - Clippings, Summer 1990 (Box 6)
  - Clippings, Summer 1989 (Box 6)
  - Bills paid, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1997 (Box 6)
  - Huck/Kononpaki – cartoons, 1988-1993 (Box 6)
  - Housing Preservation and development program, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Minority coalition, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Port Authority, undated (Box 6)
  - Economics, undated (Box 6)
  - Union publications, undated (Box 6)
  - Corruption and Mafia, undated (Box 6)
  - AUD, undated (Box 6)
  - Paper workers boycott, undated (Box 6)
  - Non-Union Jobs, undated (Box 6)
  - Davis – Bacon, undated (Box 6)
  - Contract in figures, undated (Box 6)
  - Wage Slave – world news, undated (Box 6)
  - Asbestos, undated (Box 6)
  - Labor Solidarity Network, undated (Box 6)
  - Health and safety stuff, undated (Box 6)
  - Haz. Mat., undated (Box 6)
  - Productivity in construction, undated (Box 6)
  - Women in the trade, undated (Box 6)
  - Racism, undated (Box 6)
  - Ecology, undated (Box 6)
  - Grand Central, undated (Box 6)
  - Immigration, undated (Box 6)
  - Discrimination hearings, undated (Box 6)
  - Muscatiello indictment, undated (Box 7)
  - Carpenters Construction, undated (Box 7)
  - Jack Durkan, undated (Box 7)
  - Ron Cary, undated (Box 7)
  - JFK 2000 project, undated (Box 7)
  - TDU, undated (Box 7)
  - Dust Hazards, undated (Box 7)
  - Apprentice Information, undated (Box 7)
  - 1991 contracts (Box 7)
  - Clippings – Daily News strike, undated (Box 7)
  - Anti-home port, undated (Box 7)
  - Asbestos & W.L.A. (White Lung Assoc.), undated (Box 7)
  - Economics clippings, undated (Box 7)
  - Fiber glass, undated (Box 7)
  - Poverty, undated (Box 7)
  - Union meetings, undated (Box 7)
  - Clippings, 1991 (Box 7)
  - Labor Notes, 1989 (Box 7)
  - Gulf War, undated (Box 7)
  - Hanahan letters, undated (Box 7)
  - Clippings – NYC real estate, undated (Box 7)
  - NYC trades women questionnaire, undated (Box 7)
  - Kuwait, undated (Box 7)
  - NYC water project, undated (Box 7)
  - Hanahan letters, undated (Box 7)
  - RICO, undated (Box 7)
  - RICO, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Crime, undated (Box 7)
  - Labor Militant Construction Program, undated (Box 7)
  - Kim Fellner article "In search of the movement: 60's activists in labor", 1989 (Box 7)
  - Water meter scandal, undated (Box 7)
  - Carpenters RICO suit, undated (Box 7)
  - National Stabilization Agreement, undated (Box 7)
  - 1974 vs. 530 (Drywall Tapers) vs. Cement Masons, undated (Box 7)
  - DC 9 Trusteeship (Painters), undated (Box 7)
  - Unemployed Committees, undated (Box 7)
  - Editorial meeting, 1991 (Box 7)
  - Carpenters for a stronger union, undated (Box 8)
  - North Star Grant, undated (Box 8)
  - Printing Info., undated (Box 8)
  - Bank account, 1991 (Box 8)
  - HHN & CSU, undated (Box 8)
  - Finances, 1989-1990 (Box 8)
  - P.O. Box, undated (Box 8)
  - Michael Murphy, undated (Box 8)
  - Hard Hat News Proposal, 1988 (Box 8)
  - HHN early notes, undated (Box 8)
  - San Francisco, undated (Box 8)
  - HH correspondence – NY, undated (Box 8)
  - Irene Soloway, undated (Box 8)
  - Mike Harrington, undated (Box 8)
  - Bernie Cylich, undated (Box 8)
  - Bill Moffatt, undated (Box 8)
  - Murphy’s assessment articles, undated (Box 8)
  - James McNamara, undated (Box 8)
  - John Kirkland, undated (Box 8)
  - Mark Ehrlich, undated (Box 8)
  - Jim Keaugh, undated (Box 8)
  - Martha Downes, undated (Box 8)
  - Bill Walters, undated (Box 8)
  - Bruce Belson, undated (Box 8)
  - Laborers, undated (Box 8)
  - Pick and Shovel, undated (Box 8)
  - Plumbers #2, undated (Box 8)
  - IBEW Local 3, undated (Box 8)
  - NYDC of Carpenters, undated (Box 8)
  - Carpenters 608, undated (Box 8)
  - IBEW 501, undated (Box 8)
  - NYC Central Labor Council, undated (Box 8)
  - Iron Workers, undated (Box 8)
  - Carpenters 135, undated (Box 8)
  - [Steam] Fitters 638, undated (Box 8)
  - Mail Handlers, undated (Box 8)
  - Carpenters 608, undated (Box 8)
  - [Ironworkers] 580, undated (Box 8)
  - James Bishop case [painters], undated (Box 8)
  - Painters DC9, undated (Box 8)
  - Teamsters 232, undated (Box 8)
  - Carpenters 257, undated (Box 8)
  - 530 & 17 (clippings), undated (Box 8)
  - 608 [Carpenters], undated (Box 8)
  - Operating Engineers #15, undated (Box 8)
  - Mason Tenders D.C., undated (Box 8)
  - Lathers Local 46, undated (Box 8)
  - Carpenters 531, undated (Box 8)
  - Sheet Metal L. 28, undated (Box 8)
  - Building Construction Trades Department, undated (Box 8)
  - Building Trades Council, undated (Box 8)
  - Carpenters $45 million loss, undated (Box 8)
  - House Wreckers, Local 95, undated (Box 8)
  - A.L.L Partition, undated (Box 8)
  - American Labor, undated (Box 8)
  - TAP 363 + 3, undated (Box 8)
  - Info. on construction locals, undated (Box 8)
  - Housing, undated (Box 8)
  - OSHA, undated (Box 8)
  - 12th Street redevelopment, undated (Box 9)
  - International unions, undated (Box 9)
  - Health Care Reform, undated (Box 9)
  - S.F. crane collapse, undated (Box 9)
  - ERISA & LMRDA, undated (Box 9)
  - Double breasting, undated (Box 9)
  - Union bashing, undated (Box 9)
  - Eastern Info., undated (Box 9)
  - New York COSH, undated (Box 9)
  - Americas Workingman, undated (Box 9)
  - Pensions, undated (Box 9)
  - Construction Unions, clippings & bibliography, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Massachusetts Labor, undated (Box 9)
  - Other Unions, undated (Box 9)
  - Public Housing, undated (Box 9)
  - AUD, undated (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 9)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 9)
  - CAHH News and Times, undated (Box 9)
  - Stanford and Labor Notes rank-and-file network, undated (Box 9)
  - HH9, undated (Box 9)
  - Newsletter Production, undated (Box 9)
  - Graphics, undated (Box 9)
  - Punch List, undated (Box 9)
  - Mechanicals HH, undated (Box 9)
  - Murphy, Misc., undated (Box 9)
  - Willie/Shepperson (Local 17 Carpenters), undated (Box 9)
  - NY Labor Punch Out, undated (Box 9)
  - Henry Zieger, undated (Box 9)
  - Barry Engel, undated (Box 9)
  - Cartoons, undated (Box 9)
  - Evan Ruderman, undated (Box 9)
  - Carpenters, undated (Box 9)
  - Michael Murphy, undated (Box 9)
  - Barbara Zeluck, undated (Box 9)
  - CPC and Wingham, undated (Box 9)
  - Unsorted leaflets, clippings, undated (Box 10)